and then for the long game imagine a
world where everybody understood the
full meaning of this simple idea love is
that which enables choice you really get
that if you really really get that if
you live by that principle if everybody
in the world understood that thoroughly
the world wouldn't would absolutely be a
better place as cliche as it is
you
well in that video he says love is that
which enables choice I can get in touch
with that I believe how do you respond
to that notion well that's actually a
very big question because it requires we
first be true the grok love and mutually
grok choice usually goes very grok a way
of grasping and sharing something which
is almost at the level of participating
in consciousness together sure yep with
you yep
who My heavens that is extraordinarily
sick that's a very large thing I can
read something out that might help you
if you like something you wrote
something I wrote something you wrote
that's how it's fun and I mean this is
gonna get there perhaps in a bit of a
roundabout way and I am shoehorning this
in but you know everything's connected
perhaps it is not that we need to become
conscious of power but that power needs
to become conscious of power are
becoming self-conscious of power itself
go back and look at the five orders of
power order 5 being able to create
values no longer dependent upon
pre-existing and inherited values one
can transcend the existing power systems
and begin bestowing value creating new
evaluations new distinctions but if this
is outside of the power systems from
where does this power to create values
come power looks like a geology plate
tectonics the values and power systems
that distribute them are at the surface
but that is all that they are a thin
surface resting on a molten core
occasionally this core will erupt and a
form of power will break through the
surface which is entirely new and
different
occasionally ebbs and flows in this
subterranean world will determine that
huge chunks of the surface will break
apart and flow occasionally someone will
dive down deep deep into the heart of
the world and tap into this source
herein lies power with a different name
entirely
culture is powerful but it is also many
voiced moreover all culture rests as a
thin very thin skin upon the molten core
of our human inheritance forces that
were ancient when the pyramids were
conceived rise up to ensure that will
fulfill a destiny that is beyond our
civilized vanity well haven't met that
guy in quite some time wrote that on a
train in 2002 hmm Wow
and now to connect that to forests
phrase
yeah it's um
humility I think is where it comes to me
there the the humility of really
recognizing the degree to which that
call have let nothing come between me
and love means stripping yourself down
of all that which you and anyone else
ever has constructed and being naked
before purity but for fluorescence
the holiness then of this notion choice
yeah
imagine this or think about this the
idea of free will the notion that were
the question of whether or weather or
weather we do or do not have free will
is a to me a very profane question much
more meaningful I think is to stand
amazed at the fact that that which is we
is nothing more or less than choice
which of course then would allow us to
hold the concept of sacred somewhat
simply
sacred is to enable choice to enable
choice to be furthered and then we can
do the construction mm-hmm sacred is
love love is that which enables choice
we can maybe breathe in a relationship
with the the feeling of being connected
that sense of wholeness he referred to
earlier the feeling of being part of a
continuity and also the feeling of being
each of us a moment a very precise
moment of choice
we are involved
that is meaningfulness mm-hmm whether
you're watching on YouTube or listening
as a podcast remember to subscribe and
hit the bell to track upcoming releases
myself